<resume>
  <contact>
    <name>
      <first>John</first>
      <middle>Chrisitian</middle>
      <last>Stokes</last>
    </name>
    <phone>+1 (303) 809-2260</phone>
    <email>john.stokes.co@gmail.com</email>
    <address>1017 Delta Dr</address>
    <city>Lafayette</city>
    <state>CO</state>
    <zip>80026</zip>
    <country>USA</country>
  </contact>
  <overview>
    I am a problem solver looking for the next challenge in my professional life.
    My experience centers around high performance, high throughput,
    low latency market data ticker platforms. I also have specialized in data
    processing (ETL), SQL warehousing, document management, and search solutions. I
    am now looking for my next problem to solve. I am currently teaching myself
    web and mobile applications employing AngularJS and Swift to ensure that my
    capabilities are well rounded with both front and back end development. If I
    had my dream job in uncharted waters, it would incorporate height maps,
    drone technologies, or the upcoming world of augmented reality.
  </overview>
  <employment>
    <organization>
      <name>University Corporation for Atmostpheric Research (UCAR)</name>
      <url>http://www.unidata.ucar.edu</url>
    </organization>
    <title>Systems Administrator</title>
    <team>Unidata</team>
    <duration>
      <join>2001</join>
      <leave>2005-10-30</leave>
    </duration>
    <summary>
      Student Systems Administrator at a well respected, federally funded
      reasearch labratory while studying Computer Science at the University of
      Colorado. My hobby background experience in administratoing the Linux
      operating system provided me a solid job learning how to stich together all
      major Unix platforms for a software build environment. I actively worked on
      centrally managing 30 workstations and 20 servers. Implemented Windows Active
      Directory support and incorporated LDAP/Kerberos to extend
      authentication into the Unix platforms as well. Established solid backup
      routines, automated patch updates, maintained password management, and
      generally kept a smooth running shop for a small office group of researchers.
      <br/>
      My most notable contribution was replacing an big iron sun server running
      UCAR's primary LDM server with a cheaper distributed solution. This
      project was self promoted and implemented which eventually replaced the
      single Sun server costing more than $250,000 with five commodity x86 based
      servers and an open source load balancer (LVS) costing a total of $25,000.
      I was offered a full time position as a Systems Administrator II one year
      prior to graduation, however, I declined and followed through with my
      education as a software engineer.
    </summary>
    <skills>
      <skill>System Administration</skill>
      <skill>Windows</skill>
      <skill>LDAP</skill>
      <skill>Kerberos</skill>
      <skill>Linux</skill>
      <skill>RPM</skill>
      <skill>yum</skill>
      <skill>HP/UX</skill>
      <skill>IRIX</skill>
      <skill>AIX</skill>
      <skill>Soliaris</skill>
      <skill>Active Directory</skill>
      <skill>Windows Server</skill>
      <skill>Shell Scripting</skill>
      <skill>Linux Virtual Server (LVS)</skill>
    </skills>
  </employment>
  <employment>
    <organization>
      <name>Wall Street On Demand</name>
      <url>http://www.markit.com/product/markit-on-demand</url>
    </organization>
    <title>Software Engineer</title>
    <team>Market Data Engineering</team>
    <duration>
      <join>2005-12-05</join>
      <leave>2008</leave>
    </duration>
    <summary>
      Implemented Reuter’s flagship realtime financial ticker and news
      feed, Reuters Market Data System (RMDS) for the larger organization.
      This project required an extensive mapping and rules library and engine to
      ensure that data normalization was possible as the company’s need for breadth
      in market data grew. Solely architected and implemented the configuration based
      approach, built from the ground up and provided the basis for all future
      feed development within the team.
      <br/>
      Engaged, onboarded, developed, and maintained a series of feeds through a
      suite of applications that interface with third party vendors that provide
      consolidated real-time and delayed market ticker data. Directly worked
      with data vendors Sungard, Telekurs, and Thomson Reuters. Oversaw and
      re-architected the mapping engine within the back-end quote server
      application. Normalized time series data collection and open, high, low,
      close aggregation.
      <br/>
      Designed and developed an application that simulates trade order processing
      that was used for a handful of stock market trading games and competitions.
    </summary>
    <skills>
      <skill>Object Oriented Programming</skill>
      <skill>C++</skill>
      <skill>SQL</skill>
      <skill>XML</skill>
      <skill>High Performance Computing</skill>
      <skill>Concurrency</skill>
    </skills>
  </employment>
  <employment>
    <title>Senior Software Engineer</title>
    <subtitle>Lead Senior Software Engineer</subtitle>
    <team>Access, Entitltments, and Credit Card Services</team>
    <organization>
      <name>Wall Street on Demand</name>
      <url>http://www.markit.com/product/markit-on-demand</url>
    </organization>
    <duration>
      <join>2008</join>
      <leave>2010-07</leave>
    </duration>
    <summary>
      Lead developer for the company-wide entitlements and compliance
      system. This system controlled client level, tier level, and individual
      user level compliance across any platform of data retrieval. The core
      decision making library is required to quickly make access decisions for
      high volume quote, document, news, and other data requests. The system was
      designed to be scalable to handle both growing volume and complexity of
      requirements. I was also responsible to upgrade and implement the company's
      Credit Card Processor system which was based on Pay Pal’s merchant services.
      I added capabilities for in-house subscription services without retaining
      end users credit card numbers.
    </summary>
    <skills>
      <skill>C++</skill>
      <skill>XML</skill>
      <skill>SQL</skill>
    </skills>
  </employment>
  <employment>
    <title>Director, Software Engineering Team Lead</title>
    <team>Feed Management Engineering</team>
    <organization>
      <name>Markit, Markit On Demand</name>
      <url>http://www.markit.com/product/markit-on-demand</url>
    </organization>
    <duration>
      <join>2010-07</join>
      <leave>2015-06-22</leave>
    </duration>
    <summary>
      Responsible for all non-streaming data management within the company
      with my team of 5-12 talented individuals. Our charter was to own, evolve,
      and provide the following capabilities housed within more than 30
      server applications to the larger company:
      <ul>
        <li>Custom in-house extract, transform, load (ETL) services.
          <ul>
            <li>5,000+ discreet tabular, relational, and document based feeds.</li>
            <li>Automation point for all non-streaming inbound and outbound data for the company.</li>
          </ul>
        </li>
        <li>Custom in-house Document Management System
          <ul>
            <li>Over 400M documents and over 800M files for each of three data centers.</li>
          </ul>
        </li>
        <li>Document search engine utilizing ElasticSearch multi node clusters
          housed in three data centers nationally.</li>
        <li>News and document trigger service for end users' registered filtered
          queries that resulted in email, SMS, or in page notifications.</li>
      </ul>

      <br/>
      Responsible for planning and scaling the team's application and server
      hardware needs. Provided ongoing mentoring, coaching, and guidance to
      direct reports and other software engineers. Principle archtect for all
      applications and solutions within the feeds group and consulted with many
      colleagues on general architectural guidance. Transformed the team from a
      waterfall methodology into an Agile group using two week sprints. A solid
      supporter of quick, daily stand-up meetings with the team.
    </summary>
    <skills>
      <skill>C++</skill>
      <skill>XML</skill>
      <skill>SQL</skill>
      <skill>Java</skill>
      <skill>JavaScript</skill>
      <skill>Python</skill>
      <skill>C#</skill>
      <skill>.NET</skill>
      <skill>ElasticSearch</skill>
      <skill>Management</skill>
      <skill>Software Development Life Cycle</skill>
      <skill>Agile Development</skill>
    </skills>
  </employment>
  <education>
    <program>
      <facility>University of Colorado, Boulder</facility>
      <certificate>Bachelor of Science(B.S.), Computer Science</certificate>
      <duration>
        <leave>2005-05</leave>
        YYYY-MM-DD HH:MM:SS.mmm T(-)ZZ
      </duration>
    </program>
  </education>
</resume>
